JULIET KERN

UW Biomedical Engineering Student

https://j2kern.github.io/

(647) 504 3442

in http://www.linkedin.com/ in/julietkern

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Development | React, Angular, NodeJS, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, JS, MySQL, C#, C++, Matlab

Tools | Visual Studio Code. Git

UI/UX & Design | Photoshop, AdobeXD, Axure, Figma

CAD | Solidworks, Rapid Prototyping, 3D Printing

Product Dev | Agile and Iterative design, User research, User testing

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF WATERLOO

Sept 2019 - Present

BASc For Biomedical Engineering

ST. ALOYSIUS GONZAGA

2015 - 2019

Science Award | Top graduating student in Science (extracurricular involvement)

INTERESTS

Oil Painting, Photography, Old Videography and VHS, Outdoors and Adventure

WORK EXPERIENCE

DESIGNER & FRONT END DEVELOPER

The Home Depot | May 2020 - Aug. 2020

- Canada Technology | Designed and developed a webpage for Home Depot's internal employee website for the IT department. The page displayed an informational map of the head office, prototyped with Axure and Photoshop, and developed in Angular with an integrated Google Maps API.
- Pro Store Walk Portal | Worked alongside a team to develop a heat map of the Home Depot store departments in Angular to visualize trends in sales and pinpoint opportunities for company growth. Deployed across all of the **182** Canadian Home Depot stores.

LAB ASSISTANT

York University | July 2018 - Aug. 2018

- Collected electromyography data using electrodes, processed the information using Matlab and submitted technical reports to the bioelectrical engineering professor for his research on smart clothing.

RELEVANT PROJECTS

MEMORYMAPS

Hackathon project | Jan. 2020

- Successfully developed the front-end of a website using HTML, CSS, and Google Cloud's Geolocation API that focuses on preventing people with neurological disorders such as Dementia or Alzheimer's from getting lost.
- Collaborated with team members under high-pressure and short time constraint to complete the project efficiently.

BIOMECHATRONICS DESIGN TEAM LEAD

University of Waterloo | Jan. 2020 - Apr. 2020

- Led a team of 12 to develop a sustainable powered arm prosthetic for a double amputee in El Salvador in need of device.
- Files modified in Solidworks, 3D Printed and varnished for comfort.
- Prosthetic is powered by rechargeable batteries, controlled by a programmed Arduino and connected to a linear actuator to allow for the gripping and extension of the fingers.

COMMUNITY INVOLVEMENT

STEM 50/50 PRESIDENT AND FOUNDER

St. Aloysius Gonzaga | 2018 - 2019

Provided students with fun learning opportunities, a chance to explore their interests and a platform to advocate for a more diverse future in STEM careers, with over 100 applications after our first meeting.